<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vestibule :: Suggestions for "Ruby Groups: Act Locally - Think Globally"</title>
    <description>A list of all suggestions made for "Ruby Groups: Act Locally - Think Globally"</description>
    <link>http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/39</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/39.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Suggestion from the proposer</title>
      <description type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>Nikos and Murray - The talk itself has a lot of participation (hence not needing the panel) where I rely on people from larger groups.  The idea is getting groups to contribute and I like to think everyone has a stake in doing that.  </p>

<p>Thanks for your suggestions.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 21:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/39#suggestion_98</link>
      <guid>http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/39#suggestion_98</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suggestion from Nikos Dimitrakopoulos (@)</title>
      <description type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>Maybe I push it too hard, but would it make sense to organise something like a &#39;panel&#39; for this topic if there&#39;s sufficient interest from the community? I would personally be pretty much interested.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 20:43:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/39#suggestion_95</link>
      <guid>http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/39#suggestion_95</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suggestion from Murray Steele (@h-lame)</title>
      <description type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>I organise one of the <a href="http://lrug.org/">larger and more established groups</a>, would there be anything for me in this talk?  </p>

<p>I&#39;m not suggesting that you tailor this to people already running large groups as I really do think that people just starting a group, or already organising a smaller group should take away the most from this talk, but I wonder what advice you might have for those of us involved in (or just attending) a more established group.  As I have a large pool of attendees it&#39;s not usually that hard to arrange for a couple of talks each month, but I struggle to come up with more interesting or alternative meeting ideas.</p>

<p>Finally, could you expand on what you mean by:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>making it successful so the members, as a group can contribute to the larger community</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Do you plan on covering stuff in the talk that would be useful for attendees as well as organisers?  Or is this some ideas for organisers to implement in their group to help them make it more active.  I&#39;d be interested either way, but if there are ideas that everyone (attendees and organisers alike) can use - I think you&#39;d be pitching a much more useful talk - there are certainly less organisers than there are attendees.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 20:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/39#suggestion_94</link>
      <guid>http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/39#suggestion_94</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
